autocheck.com 2017-11-03

# Your data safety and personal privacy | AutoCheck.com

**Updated: November 29, 2010**

This policy applies to AutoCheck® located at [www.autocheck.com](http://www.autocheck.com/ "AutoCheck") – Experian Automotive's Online vehicle history report service. The AutoCheck service is provided to consumers and businesses in accordance with the law and with Experian's Information Values. This privacy policy applies only to this online Web site and application(s). It does not apply to any other products or services offered through other channels.

### Personal Information Collection and Uses 

#### Consumer Information

Experian collects identifying and billing information including name, address, credit card information and e-mail address when consumers register for our AutoCheck service.

The credit card information you provide is only used for billing and customer support purposes. Experian shares this information with a credit card processing company that bills you for the transaction(s). If you do not provide all the required information, your purchase transaction(s) will not be completed and you will not receive an AutoCheck report(s). Please fill in all the required information to ensure your purchase is completed. Experian will not willfully disclose any credit card information for any other purpose, unless required to do so by law.

Any personally identifiable information you provide to us in connection with ordering your AutoCheck report online may be used by Experian Automotive to notify you of new products, product changes and enhancements. We may use collected information to make changes to our products, as deemed necessary, and to continue to ensure your security and privacy online.

Experian may also share this information with affiliated third parties, such as businesses associated with Experian.  In some circumstances, AutoCheck enables access to our services through third party Web sites, or provides access to third party services through our website. In either instance, AutoCheck may request your permission to transfer any information that you provide through us to the specified third parties or their affiliated user-recipients. In the event that you consent to this information transfer, AutoCheck makes no warranties or claims of responsibility for its use by those third parties.

#### Business Information

In addition to consumer data, Experian Automotive enables AutoCheck for dealers and commercial businesses.  This product is intended for use solely by legitimate businesses who register with, are verified and approved by, and who contractually agree to terms and conditions for appropriate use with Experian Automotive.   For authentication and verification purposes, Experian Automotive may collect additional personal information from business users including social security number or federal tax ID.

#### Non-Personal Information Collection and Uses

Experian Automotive reserves the right to share non-personal information about our customers and their transactions, including the make and model of vehicle inquiries, with affiliated or unaffiliated third parties for market research, advertising or other purposes.  

#### Use of Cookies

In order to use our online service, your Web browser must be enabled to accept “cookies”. A cookie is a text file stored by the Web browser and associated with a particular Web page or site. Cookies serve to give the Web browser a memory so that it can use data that was input on one page into another page, or so it can recall user input when the user leaves a page and later returns. We use cookies for the purpose of simplifying the registration process and enhancing the online user experience when using the AutoCheck report service. Only computer identification information will be stored in a cookie and it can only be read by our servers. We do not store any cookies on our server.

AutoCheck may enable third party Web site services organizations to access and assist with the performance and use of our Web site.  These parties may use cookies on our Web site and monitor user activities in order to measure Web site effectiveness or fulfill the services rendered as part of our affiliated relationships such as for search engine optimization and marketing efforts.  

In addition, AutoCheck has partnered with various members of the [Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/index.asp)to increase the relevance of online advertising by placing cookies and Web beacons on visitor computers associated with Web sites like AutoCheck.com. AutoCheck does not share any personal information about our users with these companies and users can choose to opt-out of their visitor information being used for online behavioral advertising purposes by referring to: http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp#

#### Website Analysis

AutoCheck maintains information about the various uses of our Web site. The primary way in which we monitor Web site activity is through the use of Web beacons. Web beacons are small image files that correspond with our Web servers indicating user activity such as; whether Web pages are viewed, how often, at specific times of day, and from specific referring pages. The Web beacons we use may be correlated with our use of cookies in order to maintain personalization and unique identification for users. Web beacons do not by themselves collect any identifiable information from Web site visitors.

AutoCheck may share Web site analysis activities with Experian and affiliated companies. AutoCheck may, in select circumstances, share anonymous Web site statistics with non-affiliated partners on a limited and as needed basis in order to measure or fulfill services rendered as part of an advertising relationship or partnership.

#### Security

Experian protects your information over the Internet by using a secure Web server, which allows your Web browser programs (Netscape Navigator/Communicator or Microsoft Internet Explorer) to interact with Experian's Web server via an encrypted session. Experian employs a Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) connection that provides an encrypted connection between your computer and Experian. The 128 bit encrypted connection scrambles ordinary text or data into cyphertext to safeguard your sensitive and private information during its journey across the Internet. The information is decrypted, or put back into a readable format, when it reaches its intended destination, your computer.

Depending on which browser you use, you will know you are in a secured area by “https” appearing in front of the URL (Uniform Resource Locator) in the address bar, and/or a locked padlock appearing somewhere in the lower corner of your screen. When you visit our Web site, you may move in and out of secured areas. Any time that you are on a registration page you will be in a secured area.

Additionally, Experian utilizes systems access controls to protect your information. Experian continually monitors access to its systems to detect unauthorized attempts to gain access to information.

Our Web site may contain links for other offers and services in which we feel you may have an interest. We believe these sites share a similar commitment to consumer privacy and urge you to review their privacy policy when visiting their sites. We cannot, however, be responsible for their privacy or security practices.

#### Accessing and Modifying Information

At any time, you have the right to contact Experian Automotive and AutoCheck to access and modify the personally identifiable information you have provided to us.

If you are subscribed to receive our email communications, each communication presents the opportunity to unsubscribe from future communications. Following your unsubscribe request, you will cease to receive email communications from us within ten business days.

For all other modification requests, please contact us at: [customersupport@experian.com](mailto:customersupport@experian.com) and type “request to change personal information". Describe in the body of email the personal information to be changed.

Experian Automotive is not responsible for access or modification of information provided to third party automotive service providers for their use.

#### Privacy policy changes

Experian reserves the right to change this privacy policy at any time and without advance notice. Therefore, we encourage you to review this privacy policy from time to time to review any changes.
